Westwood-Holmby Historical Society records, 1907-2014
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Historical Research., 1907 - 2014.
  - Research Committee., 1907 - 2010.
    - Janss: Autobiographies., undated. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Janss: Peter Janss Los Angeles Times photocopies., undated. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Janss: Scrapbook #3., undated. (Box 21)
    - Janss: Scrapbook #5., undated. (Box 25)
    - Janss: Scrapbook #7., undated. (Box 24)
    - Janss: Scrapbook #13., undated. (Box 25)
    - Janss: Scrapbook "Friends"., undated. (Box 26)
    - Janss: Westwood Community Church Memorium., undated. (Box 31)
    - Maps: Westwood photocopies., undated. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Maps: Prints of Westwood maps (medium)., undated. (Box 20)
    - Maps: Old Spanish and Mexican Ranchos of Los Angeles., undated. (Box 31)
      This map is a wood artifact.
    - Maps: Prints of Westwood maps (small)., undated. (Box 32)
      These items are mounted on foam core.
    - Narratives: Westwood., 1986 - 1995. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Narratives: Westwood Village., 1989. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Narratives: Shelley Taylor Family in Westwood., 2000. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Narratives: Westwood Park origins., undated. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Panorama: Westwood on Masonite., 1931. (Box 35)
      Original photo, 10.75" x 53.5" on Masonite. Lummis Auction purchase.
    - Panorama: Westwood Village., undated. (Box 35)
      9.75" x 65.25" copy. Has some water damage.
    - People of Westwood: Arthur Letts biography., 1927. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - People of Westwood: Arthur Letts Broadway Department Store plaque., circa 1923. (Box 18)
    - People of Westwood: White pages., 1973 - 1976. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - People of Westwood: Ron Blumberg., 1989. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Posters: Westwood Hills $5,000,000 in Building Permits Ad., 1930. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Westwood Hills Open Today Ad., undated. (Box 33)
    - Posters: The Second Hollywood Westwood aerial drawing Ad., undated. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Rancho San Vicente y Santa Monica., 1881. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Westwood Hills and Holmby Hills map., 1931. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Early Westwood subdivision map., undated. (Box 33)
    - Posters: San Jose de Buenos Ayres., 1858. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Rancho San Jose de Buenos Ayres., undated. (Box 33)
    - Posters: The Historic Ranchos of Los Angeles (color)., undated. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Mar Pacifico Del Norte, old map of Ranchos Viscente., undated. (Box 33)
    - Posters: Westwood Hills Ad., 1928. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Westwood Hills Smart Investment Ad., 1931. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Holmby Hills, Janss Investment Corporation., 1926. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Westwood Everyone Working Overtime Ad., 1922. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Westwood Ad., 1924. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Westwood, The New City Ad., 1923. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Streets of Old Monterey Unit. Westwood Hills Ad., 1930. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Three New Homes In Westwood Hills Ad., 1935. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Unit 2 of Fox Hills, Open Westwood Today Ad., 1923. (Box 34)
    - Posters: Holmby Hills, Residential Estates Ad., 1926. (Box 34)
    - Photocopies: Research., 1989. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Photocopies: Research., undated. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Photocopies: Research., undated. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Preservation: Historic Cultural Monuments., 1987 - 1994. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Preservation: Research In The City of Los Angeles Survey., 1989. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Preservation: News., 1991 - 1993. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Preservation: Guide., February 1992. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Preservation: Resources., undated. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Preservation: Cultural Heritage Master Plan., undated. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Preservation: Cultural Monuments of Conservation., undated. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Publications: Westwood Hills., 1940. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Publications: Westwood Notices and News., 1975 - 2004. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Publications: Eugene Gilbert Evening Outlook reprint copies., 1978 - 1988. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Publications: Westways Article., 1992. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Publications: Village Update., 1998 - 1999. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - UCLA: The Architect and Engineer., 1930. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - UCLA: History of James Martin., 1940 - 1974. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Westwood Photographs: Rancho Days., 1907 - 1924. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood Early Development., 1921 - 1927. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Westwood Photographs: UCLA., 1929. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood Blvd., 1925 - 1955. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Westwood Photographs: UCLA., 1929. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Westwood Photographs: Advertisements and news clippings., 1929. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Westwood Photographs: Panoramic Photographs I., 1929 - 1933. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Westwood Photographs: Panoramic Photographs II., 1929 - 1933. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Westwood Photographs: UCLA Masonic Club., 1929 - 1957. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Westwood Photographs: Glendon Ave., circa 1930. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Westwood Photographs: Janss Drug Tower., circa 1930. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Westwood Photographs: Royce Hall with Goodyear Blimp., circa 1930. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood Blvd., circa 1930. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Westwood Photographs: Aerial Views., 1931 - 1940. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Westwood Photographs: Janss Tower., 1932 - 1954. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Westwood Photographs: Gas stations., 1935 - 1936. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Westwood Photographs: People., 1935 - 1940. (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood Courtyards., 1935 - 1947. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood Buildings., 1935 - 1962. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Westwood Photographs: Janss Dome., 1937 - 1954. (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Westwood Photographs: South of Wilshire., 1937 - 1954. (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Westwood Photographs: USC Hearst Collection of Westwood., circa 1938. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Westwood Photographs: Theatres., 1938. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Westwood Photographs: Wilshire., 1939 - 1970. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Westwood Photographs: Janss Dome., circa 1940. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Westwood Photographs: Movie premiere of "Adventures of Casanova"., 1948. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Westwood Photographs: Ice Skating Rink., circa 1950. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Westwood Photographs: Bullock's Westwood., 1955. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Westwood Photographs: Architecture., circa 1990s. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Westwood Photographs: Historical Society Slide Show I., undated. (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Contains 35mm positive film.
    - Westwood Photographs: Historical Society Slide Show II., undated. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Westwood Photographs: Copies from UCLA Collection., undated. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood Photos with captions., undated. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Westwood Photographs: Westwood and Los Angeles Homes., undated. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Westwood Photographs: Oversize prints., circa 1930s - 1940s. (Box 27)
    - Westwood Photographs: Negatives and contact prints., circa 1920s - 1950s. (Box 28)
      Contains medium format film negatives.
  - Oral Histories., 1989 - 2000.
    The oral histories in this subseries were recorded interviews conducted by the WHHS between the years of 1989 and 1992. Also included is a two volume bound transcript of separate interviews conducted by the UCLA Center for Oral History Research.
    SUBSERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - Oral Histories: Rowe Baldwin Interview., 1989. (Box 28)
      Contains three cassette tapes.
    - Oral Histories: KSRF Interview on Westwood 60th Anniversary., 1989. (Box 28)
      Contains one cassette tape.
    - Oral Histories: Mabel Jellison Burbank., 1992. (Box 28)
      Contains two micro cassettes.
    - Oral Histories: Greg Fischer and Rubi Chatalian Interviews., undated. (Box 28)
    - Oral Histories: Westwood Past Present and Future., November 14, 1990. (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Contains one VHS tape.
    - Oral Histories: Westwood Pioneers Volume 1, Volume 2., 2000. (Box 15)